<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://rmunro.nl/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://rmunro.nl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-18T07:26:57+00:00</updated><id>https://rmunro.nl/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ronan’s Collection</title><subtitle>Collection blog</subtitle><author><name>Ronan Munro</name></author><entry><title type="html">Accuracy of diagonal mouse paths</title><link href="https://rmunro.nl/assignment/2021/05/18/accuracyMouse.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accuracy of diagonal mouse paths" /><published>2021-05-18T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-18T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://rmunro.nl/assignment/2021/05/18/accuracyMouse</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://rmunro.nl/assignment/2021/05/18/accuracyMouse.html">&lt;p&gt;During our day-to-day life we constantly use computers.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; To improve our efficiency, programs should be ergonomically optimized to increase speed when using the program.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; This can be done by maximising the accuracy of the user when using the program.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The accuracy of a user can be measured in the form of the maximum width of the mouse path when using the program.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; For laptop users, what path angles should be preferred or avoided?&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; So; Do laptop users on average have the same accuracy with a diagonal mouse path compared to a straight mouse path?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-star&quot; id=&quot;methods&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#methods&quot; class=&quot;heading&quot;&gt;Methods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dataset used for this experiment was a mouse test done by students at the Eindhoven University of Technology.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Outliers of the dataset were removed, by only keeping the 99th percentile of the data whilst keeping maximum data.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; For this experiment, only trackpad users were selected as this is the group where the highest gain in efficiency can be achieved.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; All paths were either grouped into a ‘Diagonal’ or ‘Straight’ angle types.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; To compare the means of these groups, a two-sample t-test was used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-star&quot; id=&quot;hypothesis&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hypothesis&quot; class=&quot;heading&quot;&gt;Hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;equation&quot;&gt;\[ H_0: \mu_{width straight} = \mu_{width diagonal} \]
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;equation&quot;&gt;\[ H_a: \mu_{width straight} &amp;gt; \mu_{width diagonal} \]
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;uid1&quot; data-tralics-id=&quot;uid1&quot; data-number=&quot;1&quot; class=&quot;figure&quot; noindent=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;graphics&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/accuracyMouse/pathsEdited.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;pathsEdited&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;header&quot;&gt;Figure 1: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Mouse trajectory paths - all trials&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;fig-dist&quot; data-tralics-id=&quot;uid2&quot; data-number=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;graphics&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/accuracyMouse/Distribution.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Distribution&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;header&quot;&gt;Figure 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-star&quot; id=&quot;discussion&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#discussion&quot; class=&quot;heading&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mouse trajectory paths shows trajectories in all directions, so there are no direction assumptions.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The dataset has a length of more than thirteen thousand and is large enough.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Even still the length of the dataset is large, the cleaned also follows a distribution curve.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; For all these reasons, the two-sample t-test is valid and applied.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The p-value is (a lot) smaller than an alpha of 0.05, for a 95% confidence interval.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The null hypothesis (&lt;span class=&quot;inline_math&quot;&gt;\( 𝐻_0 \)&lt;/span&gt;) is rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-star&quot; id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#conclusion&quot; class=&quot;heading&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The null hypothesis (&lt;span class=&quot;inline_math&quot;&gt;\( 𝐻_0 \)&lt;/span&gt;) is rejected based on that the p-value is much smaller than an alpha of 0.05, and the alternative hypothesis (&lt;span class=&quot;inline_math&quot;&gt;\( 𝐻_𝑎 \)&lt;/span&gt;) is accepted.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Meaning, the mean width of trajectories that are straight is lower, and the mean of diagonal trajectories are larger.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Trackpad users are less accurate for diagonal trajectories.&lt;span class=&quot;intersentencespace&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; For using a program, this means that diagonal trajectories should be avoided to aid in maximising accuracy and therefor efficiency.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ronan Munro</name></author><category term="assignment" /><summary type="html">During our day-to-day life we constantly use computers. To improve our efficiency, programs should be ergonomically optimized to increase speed when using the program. This can be done by maximising the accuracy of the user when using the program. The accuracy of a user can be measured in the form of the maximum width of the mouse path when using the program. For laptop users, what path angles should be preferred or avoided? So; Do laptop users on average have the same accuracy with a diagonal mouse path compared to a straight mouse path? Methods The dataset used for this experiment was a mouse test done by students at the Eindhoven University of Technology. Outliers of the dataset were removed, by only keeping the 99th percentile of the data whilst keeping maximum data. For this experiment, only trackpad users were selected as this is the group where the highest gain in efficiency can be achieved. All paths were either grouped into a ‘Diagonal’ or ‘Straight’ angle types. To compare the means of these groups, a two-sample t-test was used. Hypothesis \[ H_0: \mu_{width straight} = \mu_{width diagonal} \] \[ H_a: \mu_{width straight} &amp;gt; \mu_{width diagonal} \] Figure 1: Mouse trajectory paths - all trials Figure 2 Discussion The mouse trajectory paths shows trajectories in all directions, so there are no direction assumptions. The dataset has a length of more than thirteen thousand and is large enough. Even still the length of the dataset is large, the cleaned also follows a distribution curve. For all these reasons, the two-sample t-test is valid and applied. The p-value is (a lot) smaller than an alpha of 0.05, for a 95% confidence interval. The null hypothesis (\( 𝐻_0 \)) is rejected. Conclusion The null hypothesis (\( 𝐻_0 \)) is rejected based on that the p-value is much smaller than an alpha of 0.05, and the alternative hypothesis (\( 𝐻_𝑎 \)) is accepted. Meaning, the mean width of trajectories that are straight is lower, and the mean of diagonal trajectories are larger. Trackpad users are less accurate for diagonal trajectories. For using a program, this means that diagonal trajectories should be avoided to aid in maximising accuracy and therefor efficiency.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First post!</title><link href="https://rmunro.nl/post/2021/05/17/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First post!" /><published>2021-05-17T18:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-17T18:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://rmunro.nl/post/2021/05/17/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://rmunro.nl/post/2021/05/17/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first post to come to this blog. This blog will mostly include projects and personal intrests. Just a place holder, hopefully removed in the future ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ronan Munro</name></author><category term="post" /><summary type="html">This is the first post to come to this blog. This blog will mostly include projects and personal intrests. Just a place holder, hopefully removed in the future ;)</summary></entry></feed>